Nothing stays lost forever.
The Dig is a drama, history film directed by Simon Stone.
As WWII looms, a wealthy widow hires an amateur archaeologist
to excavate the burial mounds on her estate.
When they make a historic discovery, the echoes of Britain's past
resonate in the face of its uncertain future‎.
Edith Pretty, played by Carey Mulligan.
Basil Brown, played by Ralph Fiennes.
Peggy Piggott, played by Lily James.
Rory Lomax, played by Johnny Flynn.
Stuart Piggott, played by Ben Chaplin.
Charles Phillips, played by Ken Stott.
The Dig is a 2021 British drama film directed by Simon Stone, based on the 2007 historical novel of the same name by
John Preston, which reimagines the events of the 1939 excavation of Sutton Hoo in Suffolk, England.
It stars Carey Mulligan, Ralph Fiennes, Lily James, Johnny Flynn, Ben
Chaplin, Ken Stott, Archie Barnes, and Monica Dolan.
It had a limited release on 14 January 2021, followed by
streaming on Netflix on 29 January 2021.
The film received positive reviews from critics and received five nominations for
the British Academy Film Awards, including Outstanding British Film.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, excavation,
single parent, based on true story, class differences.
The tone is emotional.